Curtis Cook Zuni Pueblo storytelling collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series III: Photographs
  - Aerial view of Blackrock, site of the Indian Health Service hospital and a small number of residences 5 miles east of Zuni village, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 26 (Box 5)
  - Rainbow over the north end of Dowa Yalanne, with remnants of a stone wall in the foreground, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 27 (Box 5)
  - A small stone house on highway 53, 10 miles east of Zuni, 1963-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 28 (Box 5)
  - Abandoned stone house with Kwili Yala:we ("Twin Buttes") in the background, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 29 (Box 5)
  - Malapai stone house under construction in the main village, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 30 (Box 5)
  - Adobe bricks used in construction of many Zuni homes, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 31 (Box 5)
  - Cinder block home in Zuni village, 1963-1967, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 32 (Box 5)
  - Stone and cinder block home located at the junction of highway 53 and the road going to the south side of the river, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 33 (Box 5)
  - A home my family shared with an elderly Zuni couple when we first moved to Zuni on January 1, 1964, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 34 (Box 5)
  - Winters at Zuni, 1964, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 35 (Box 5)
    Winters at Zuni can be very cold. On the day we arrived in 1964, the temperature was 10 degrees below zero, and there was ice and snow on the ground
  - 100 year-old adobe house behind Kelsey Trading Post, 1964-1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 36 (Box 5)
    About 9 months after we moved to Zuni, we moved into this 100 year-old adobe house located behind Kelsey Trading Post. Pat Kelsey had offered us the house rent-free. I put in floor joists and a new hardwood floor, and we painted the entire inside of this three-room adobe place that had once been used to house U. S. Cavalry Soldiers.
  - Three-bedroom house behind the Vanderwagen Trading Post, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 37 (Box 5)
    Early in 1965, we moved to this three-bedroom house behind the Vanderwagen Trading Post. The house was graciously offered to us rent-free by Ernie Vanderwagen, owner of the trading post.
  - We found this house to be very comfortable, with propane heat and more space for our family. Today, the house is rented out as a bed and breakfast at Zuni, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 38 (Box 5)
  - In 1972 we moved to this house at Blackrock, where I could have a separate room designated as my study, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 39 (Box 5)
  - Blackrock reservoir, 1963-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 40 (Box 5)
  - A series of mud ovens (usually one for each married woman in a household). Zuni sacred mountain in the background, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 41 (Box 5)
  - A Zuni woman with her mud oven under construction, 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 42 (Box 5)
  - Ovens built on a raised platform for the convenience of the bread-maker, 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 43 (Box 5)
  - Two ovens illustrating that some of the walls of the oven are made of laid-up malapai stone, then coated with mud on the outside, 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 44 (Box 5)
  - A fire is built to get the oven hot, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 45 (Box 5)
  - The fire is left to burn for a couple hours, 1968-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 46 (Box 5)
  - Then, after the fire is extinguished, the ashes are raked out, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 47 (Box 5)
  - The bottom of the oven is swabbed with water using an evergreen mop, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 48 (Box 5)
  - Meanwhile, white kid (David Cook) and dog wait, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 49 (Box 5)
  - The dough is brought out on boards to be placed in the oven, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 50 (Box 5)
  - Young girls assist, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 51 (Box 5)
  - The bread begins to go into the oven, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 52 (Box 5)
  - Bread being placed in the oven, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 53 (Box 5)
  - Bread being placed into the oven, 1968-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 54 (Box 5)
  - Bread in the oven. Sometimes as many as 20 loaves will be baked in the oven at one time, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 55 (Box 5)
  - The door of the oven will be closed using boards and an old coat or blanket to keep the heat in, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 56 (Box 5)
  - After about two hours, the bread is fully baked, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 57 (Box 5)
  - The tasty loaves of bread will go really well with mutton stew, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 58 (Box 5)
  - Fire burning in the oven (extra slide), 1968-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 59 (Box 5)
  - Raking out the ashes (extra), 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 60 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne ("corn mountain"), the Zuni sacred mountain, 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 61 (Box 5)
    Regarded as sacred because of its prominence in Zuni oral history and because it is the site of sacred religious shrines.
  - Dowa Yalanne in the distance, at mid-day, 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 62 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, late afternoon, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 63 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, as the sun sets, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 64 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, in the winter, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 65 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, a winter landscape, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 66 (Box 5)
  - Clouds gather over Dowa Yalanne, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 67 (Box 5)
  - Last vestiges of light on Dowa Yalanne before nightfall, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 68 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, reflecting the sun on an overcast day, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 69 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, framed by a rainbow and hand-hewn rock in the foreground, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 70 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne rises more than 1,000 feet from the valley floor, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 71 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, with a rainbow rising above Dimu:shi Yala:we ("arrowhead mountains") to the left and an old fence post in the foreground, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 72 (Box 5)
  - Dowa Yalanne, framed again by an "amidolanne" (rainbow), 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 73 (Box 5)
  - Access to the top of Dowa Yalanne is from the east side through a narrow crevice, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 74 (Box 5)
  - On top, there are ruins of an old village, the village of Kwakina, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 75 (Box 5)
  - At the south end of the mountain, many petroglyphs can be seen high on a ledge about 1/3 or the way up, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 76 (Box 5)
  - Aerial view, coming in from the west, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 77 (Box 5)
  - Approaching the south end, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 78 (Box 5)
  - The ancient village of Kwakina (not visible from this shot) is located just above the convergence of cliff walls, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 79 (Box 5)
    The ancient village of Kwakina (not visible from this shot) is located just above the convergence of cliff walls. There are hand and footholds in the steep crevice leading down to a spring, where women descended to collect water and bring it back up to the top.
  - Continuing around the south side, a final view of the top of Dowa Yalanne, 1965-1976, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 80 (Box 5)
  - Dirt road to A'laho'ankwi ("red rock place") to the south, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 81 (Box 5)
  - Dirt road leading from Ojo Caliente to the village. The road is referred to as "dalalanaye," or "washboard road," 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 82 (Box 5)
  - Road leading to the village late evening, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 83 (Box 5)
  - Night settles in over the valley, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 84 (Box 5)
  - View of the fields from the top of the water tank mountain, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 85 (Box 5)
  - A winter village scene; privy in foreground, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 86 (Box 5)
  - Flowers blooming in the early spring at Blackrock, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 87 (Box 5)
  - Daffodils in the snow, 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 88 (Box 5)
  - Sandstone and limestone reflect the light, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 89 (Box 5)
  - The deep blue sky of Zuni country and mountain shadows, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 90 (Box 5)
  - Welcome clouds that bring rain, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 91 (Box 5)
  - Ruin of an old stone structure, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 92 (Box 5)
  - Twin Buttes with stone house in foreground, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 93 (Box 5)
  - Twin Buttes with stone house in foreground (extra), 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 94 (Box 5)
  - Small stone house 10 miles east of Zuni, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 95 (Box 5)
  - Drought takes its toll on Zuni livestock, 1965-1978, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 96 (Box 5)
  - Clouds over Zuni country, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 97 (Box 5)
  - The mist begins to fall, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 98 (Box 5)
  - Wilo'ananne ("lightning"), 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 99 (Box 5)
  - Finally, the waters flow, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 100 (Box 5)
  - Summer sunset at Zuni, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 101 (Box 5)
  - Winter sunset, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 102 (Box 5)
  - Hish dewutso'ya ("It's beautiful"), 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 103 (Box 5)
  - Skies painted by the Master Artist, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 104 (Box 5)
  - Frosty fields at sunset, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 105 (Box 5)
  - Warm red skies, 1965-1966, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 106 (Box 5)
  - A room with a view, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 107 (Box 5)
  - The Creator put us in a beautiful place, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 108 (Box 5)
  - Double rainbow over Blackrock reservoir, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 109 (Box 5)
  - Rainbow over Dimu:shi Yala:we ("Arrowhead Mountains"), 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 110 (Box 5)
  - The other end of rainbow #109, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 111 (Box 5)
  - The village in winter, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 112 (Box 5)
  - Ruins of the Zuni Catholic mission, originally built circa 1620, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 113 (Box 5)
  - Catholic mission being renovated, 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 114 (Box 5)
  - The renovation almost complete, 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 115 (Box 5)
  - Finally completed, the mission is an imposing structure in the heart of old Zuni village, Idiwanakwi ("The Middle Place"), 1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 116 (Box 5)
  - The Christian Reformed Mission, established in 1897, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 117 (Box 5)
  - Burned to the ground in the spring of 1971, 1965-1971, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 118 (Box 5)
  - The Christian Reformed Church and school, rebuilt 1972, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 119 (Box 5)
  - The small Southern Baptist Mission met here from 1967 to 1974, when a new facility was built on the outskirts of the main village, 1967-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 120 (Box 5)
  - A Zuni Cacique leading the Zuni entry at the Gallup Intertribal Ceremonial, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 121 (Box 5)
  - A Zuni Rainbow Dancer, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 122 (Box 5)
  - Zuni Olla Maidens at Zuni parade, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 123 (Box 5)
  - Zuni Olla Maidens at the Gallup Intertribal Cermonial, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 124 (Box 5)
  - Zuni Butterfly Dancers at Zuni parade, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 125 (Box 5)
  - Zuni Corn Maidens at Zuni parade, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 126 (Box 5)
  - More Zuni Dancers, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 127 (Box 5)
  - More Zuni Dancers, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 128 (Box 5)
  - Zuni Tribal Band, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 129 (Box 5)
  - Drummers and singers follow, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 130 (Box 5)
  - More young Zuni Dancers, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 131 (Box 5)
  - An Olla Maiden at the Intertribal Ceremonial, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 132 (Box 5)
  - Colorful regalia in the 1970 parade at Zuni, 1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 133 (Box 5)
  - More Zuni Dancers, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 134 (Box 5)
  - Intergenerational entry in the parade, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 135 (Box 5)
  - More Zuni Dancers, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 136 (Box 5)
  - Not given, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 137 (Box 5)
  - Robert Lastyone travels with two horsepower, and one-barrel carburetor, 1965-1969, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 138 (Box 5)
  - Some of the kids hitch-hike, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 139 (Box 5)
  - But the Zuni Fair Queen and her Court ride in style, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 140 (Box 5)
  - Peter Neha, adobe brick maker, and father of fourteen, the dirt to begin the process, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 141 (Box 5)
  - Next he adds water and begins to mix in the straw, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 142 (Box 5)
  - The straw helps to make the bricks stronger and more durable, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 143 (Box 5)
  - Peter is a poor man, but he must mix in enough straw to deliver a quality product, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 144 (Box 5)
  - Having poured the mixture into molds, he now removes the molds and begins to lay out the bricks to dry in the warm sun, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 145 (Box 5)
  - Peter sometimes made as many as two thousand bricks to fill a single order, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 146 (Box 5)
  - It's a big enough task that he needs help, so his mother has joined him, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 147 (Box 5)
  - After the bricks have dried sufficiently, Peter begins to stack them for loading on the customer's pick-up, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 148 (Box 5)
  - More adobe bricks ready to be stacked and loaded, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 149 (Box 5)
  - A few Zuni men raise cattle and graze them on designated grazing allotments on the 440,000-acre reservation, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 150 (Box 5)
  - Other men raise horses, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 151 (Box 5)
  - In the fall of the year or early winter, the Zuni Tribal Stock Pens are alive with activity, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 152 (Box 5)
  - Sheep, a mainstay of the Zuni economy, are brought to the stock pens to be loaded and shipped to market in Albuquerque, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 153 (Box 5)
  - The sheep seem to know what's happening, so it takes some encouragement to get them to go through the chute, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 154 (Box 5)
  - Herded into the loading pen where they are counted and then loaded onto trucks, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 155 (Box 5)
  - In the early to mid-70's there was an Ampex Electronics assembly plant at Blackrock, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 156 (Box 5)
  - The plant employed dozens of Zuni people, 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 157 (Box 5)
  - The plant supervisor told me that Zunis do better soldering work than any machine Ampex could develop, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 158 (Box 5)
  - The Zunis, with their skill in working with silver, had just the experience needed to make the plant productive, 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 159 (Box 5)
  - Ultimately, the plant closed..., 1965-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 160 (Box 5)
    Ultimately, the plant closed, as many of the Zuni employees found that they could make a better living staying at home and doing their work with silver and turquoise. Note: The silver and turquoise craftsmanship of the Zunis is exquisite, and is the primary source of income for most Zuni households. Their pottery work, too, is considered to be among the finest made. For this reason, I have taken the liberty to include some commercially produced slides that illustrate their work (see slide #'s 181-196). These may, or may not, be usable for purposes of the collection.
  - A Zuni infant resting on a bench as the Zuni parade goes by, 1965-1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 161 (Box 5)
  - A Zuni pre-schooler at Head Start graduation, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 162 (Box 5)
  - Other Head Start graduates, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 163 (Box 5)
  - Zuni children outside the Christian Reformed Mission School, 1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 164 (Box 5)
  - Zuni children in a mission school program, 1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 165 (Box 5)
  - Zuni children on a summer day, 1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 166 (Box 5)
  - Zuni children on a rooftop by the old plaza, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 167 (Box 5)
  - Two Zuni Head Start boys, glad to be graduating, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 168 (Box 5)
  - Some kids would rather just go fishing, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 169 (Box 5)
  - Zuni River becomes a playground, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 170 (Box 5)
  - Little children at play in Zuni River, 1970, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 171 (Box 5)
  - Children at play near an old stone house, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 172 (Box 5)
  - A little girl in front of a hand-hewn malapai stone house, 1965-1968, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 173 (Box 5)
  - Christine Cook and her Zuni friend (granddaughter of our elderly landlords, Weekema and Ida Eriacho) in their mantas, made for them by Ida Eriacho, 1964, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 174 (Box 5)
  - Three children in the village, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 175 (Box 5)
  - Great granddaughter of Owaleon Nash, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 176 (Box 5)
  - Zuni 7th grade boys who helped to write Ho'n A:wan Delapna:we ("Our Stories") at the Christian Reformed Mission School, 1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 177 (Box 5)
  - Kelsey Trading Post on "Give-away Day" (an annual event when traders toss dry goods, food and other gifts from the rooftops as a thank you to the people), 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 178 (Box 5)
  - The give-away always draws a crowd, 1965, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 179 (Box 5)
  - The crowd gathers at Vanderwagen Trading Post too, 1965-1972, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 180 (Box 5)
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 181 (Box 5)
    A Jim Abeita painting of a silversmith at work
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 182 (Box 5)
    A Jim Abeita painting showing a prize-winning inlay belt
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 183 (Box 5)
    Zuni cluster turquoise bracelets
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 184 (Box 5)
    Inlaid concho belts and bracelet
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 185 (Box 5)
    Zuni inlay bola ties
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 186 (Box 5)
    Zuni inlay dancing figures
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 187 (Box 5)
    Zuni inlay in abalone shell
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 188 (Box 5)
    Zuni rainbow god necklace
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 189 (Box 5)
    Zuni carved fetishes
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 190 (Box 5)
    Janice Bowekaty (spelling on back of slide is incorrect) in her finest
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 191 (Box 5)
    Zuni fetish necklace
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 192 (Box 5)
    Jemez Pueblo Rainbow dancer in costume similar to Zuni ceremonial wear
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 193 (Box 5)
    Fine Zuni needlepoint bracelet, ring and pendant
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 194 (Box 5)
    Hopi pot, similar to those produced at Zuni.
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 195 (Box 5)
    Fine Zuni pottery, with squash blossom and deer/heart-line
  - Commercially produced slide of Zuni craftsmenship, 1968-1973, 35 mm color slide; AFC 2004/010: 196 (Box 5)
    Hopi pots, similar in design to what you would find at Zuni
  - Lorenzo Chavez at about 95-98 years old, 1965-1978, 10" x 8" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph1 (Box 5)
    Primary language helper in the translation work, and original storyteller of Chummali dap Suski (the Locust and the Coyote) and other stories in the small published book titled Suski.
  - Lorenzo Chavez with Curtis Cook, translator, 1965-1978, 10" x 7.5" black and white print; AFC 2004/010: ph2 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo Chavez with Curtis Cook at the translation desk, 1965-1978, 5" x 7" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph3 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo gesturing during a story about warriors fighting, one of them striking another, "yakdohkya" ("he hit him"), 1965-1978, 5" x 7" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph4 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo in the same story as #4, 1965-1978, 3.5" x 5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph5 (Box 5)
  - Peter Neha, occasional translation helper, with Curtis Cook, 1965-1978, 3.5" x 5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph6 (Box 5)
  - Rex Chimoni, another primary language helper, who also served as native pastor of the Christian Reformed Church at Zuni, 1965-1978, 3" x 4.5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph7 (Box 5)
  - Small photo of Lorenzo at his home at Ojo Caliente, 1965-1978, 2" x 2" color print.; AFC 2004/010: ph8 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo Chavez and Curtis Cook at Ojo Caliente, 1965-1978, 3.5" x 5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph9 (Box 5)
  - Close-up of Lorenzo at Ojo Caliente, 1965-1978, 3.5" x 5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph10 (Box 5)
  - Lorenzo's house at Ojo Caliente, 1965-1978, 3.5" x 5" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph11 (Box 5)
  - Curtis Cook distributing copies of the Gospel fo Mark Zuni translation and the booklet Suski, 1965-1978, 10" x 8" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph12 (Box 5)
  - Curtis Cook reciting a portion of the translated books, 1965-1978, 10" x 8" color print; AFC 2004/010: ph13 (Box 5)